https://thedottyhouse.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Go to checkout
Christmas Christmas CardsChristmas WrappingOccasions Anniversary GiftsBaby Shower GiftsChristening GiftsEngagement GiftsFather's DayGet Well Soon GiftsHousewarming GiftsNew Baby GiftsRetirement GiftsThank You GiftsThinking Of You GiftsWedding GiftsHis PersonalisedHers BagsGiftsHeadbandsJewelleryJoma BraceletsKey RingsKimono / WrapsPersonalisedScarvesKids PersonalisedGifts for BabiesGifts for BoysGifts for GirlsJellycatHouse & Home CushionsOutdoorPersonalised GiftsAlcohol RelatedHome AccessoriesHome FragrancePictures and PrintsCards & Gift Bags Adult Age Birthday CardsAnniversary CardsBaby Shower CardsBelated BirthdayBirthday CardsBlank Greetings CardsChildren's Age Birthday CardsChristening / Naming Day CardsCondolence CardsCongratulations/ Well Done CardsEngagement CardsFather's Day CardsFemale Relative Birthday CardsGeordie CardsGet Well Soon CardsGift Bags & WrapGood Luck CardsHere for You CardsLeaving / Bon Voyage CardsLockdown CardsMale Relative Birthday CardsNew Baby CardsNew Home CardsNew Job CardsRetirement CardsThank You CardsThinking of You CardWedding CardsX-Rated Top Shelf Cards
Gift ideas for all of the family
Free delivery on orders over £40
Personalised unique gifts
Home >
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
The Dotty House respects your privacy
Your privacy is important to us.
This privacy statement explains what personal data The Dotty House collects from you, through our interactions with you and how we use that data.
This statement applied to The Dotty House’s interactions with you and the services listed below:
Personal Data we collect
How We Use Personal Data
How to Access & control Your Personal Data
Any personal information you provide to us including and similar to your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of The Dotty House.
Personal Data That We Collect
The Dotty House collects data to operate effectively and provide you with services best suited to your individual needs.
You have choices about the data we collect.  When you are asked to provide personal data, you may decline, but if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to deliver our services in full to you, the service delivered may be limited.
The data we collect depends on the context of the services you require to be delivered from our company, the choices you make, including protecting your privacy, and the products and services you use.  The data we collect can include the following:
Name and Contact Data – We collect your first name and last name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone number and other similar contact data.
How we Use Personal Data
The Dotty House uses the data we collect for three basic purposes:
To operate our business
Provide our service to you
To send communications to you
In carrying out these purposes we collect data to give you information about our services.
Providing and improving our products
We use data to provide and improve the services we offer and to improve essential business operations. This includes delivering our services, maintaining & improving the performance of our Services and products, developing our customer service, conducting research and providing customer support.  Examples of such uses include the following:
Providing Services – we use data to carry out your instructions with us and to provide our services to you.
Client support – We use data to provide customer care and support services.
Provision of Services – We use data to provide our services that have been agreed with you.
Service Improvement – We use data to continually improve our services to you.
Business Operations – we use data to develop, analyse and feed into business intelligence that enables us to operate, protect and make informed decisions and report on the performance of our business.
Communications – We use data we collect to communicate with you and personalise our communications with you.
Reasons We Share Personal Data
We share your personal data with your consent.
We will access, transfer, disclose and preserve personal data, when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to:
Comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal processes, including from law enforcement or other government agencies;
Protect our customers, for example to prevent spam or attempts to defraud users of our services;
Operate and maintain the security of our services, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks; or
protect the rights or property of The Dotty House, including enforcing the terms governing the use of our services;
How to Access & Control Your Personal Data
You can request to view, edit or delete your personal data by contacting our office, in writing, at The Dotty House.
Cookies
Our website uses cookies which are small text files that originate from us and are stored on your computer or website server. They do not retrieve information about you that is stored on your hard drive and do not corrupt or damage your computer or computer files. They help us identify website visitor behaviour and visitors’ particular preferences.
The table below explains the cookies we use and why.
Cookie
Name
Purpose
More information
Google Analytics
_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmz
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to
compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form,
including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they
visited.
Click here for an overview of
privacy at Google
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Credit Card details
The Dotty House will never ask for Credit Card details and request that you do not enter it on any of the forms on the The Dotty House website.
External Sites
The Dotty House is not responsible for the content of external internet sites. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.
Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet
While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to The Dotty House and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition other Internet sites or services that may be accessible through The Dotty House have separate data and privacy practices independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions. Please contact those vendors and others directly if you have any questions
about their privacy policies.
Other Important Privacy Information
Below, you will find additional privacy information that you may find important.
European Privacy Rights
The Dotty House adheres to applicable data protection laws in the European Economic Area, which if applicable includes the following rights:
If the processing of personal data is based on your consent, you have a right to withdraw consent at any time for future processing;
You have a right to request from us, a “data controller” as defined in the law, access to and rectification of
your personal data;
You have a right to object to the processing of your personal data; and
You have a right to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority.
When we process personal data about you, we do so with your consent and/or as necessary to provide the services/products you use, operate our business, meet our contractual and legal obligations, protect the security of our systems and our customers, or fulfill other legitimate interests of The Dotty House as described in the “How We Use Personal Data” and “Reasons We Share Personal Data” sections above. When we transfer personal data from the European Economic Area, we do so based on a variety of legal mechanisms, as described in “Where We Store and Process Personal Data” below.
Security of Personal Data
The Dotty House is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities held within two locations within the UK. When we transmit highly confidential data over the links to cloud apps into one app which your client can download.
Where We Store and Process Personal Data
Personal data collected by The Dotty House will be held securely and we take steps to ensure that the data we collect under this privacy statement is processed according to the provisions of this statement and the requirements of applicable UK & EU law.
Our Retention of Personal Data
The Dotty House retains personal data for as long as necessary to provide the products and fulfill the transactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes and enforcing our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different products, actual retention periods can vary significantly. The criteria used to determine the retention periods include:
How long is the personal data needed to provide the products and operate our business? Is the personal data of a sensitive type? If so, a shortened retention time would generally be appropriate.
Has The Dotty House adopted and announced a specific retention period for a certain data type?
Changes to This Privacy Statement
We will update this privacy statement when necessary to reflect customer feedback and changes in our services/products. When we post changes to this statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of the statement and describe the changes. If there are material changes to the statement or in how The Dotty House will use your personal data, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to learn how The Dotty House is protecting your information.
How to Contact Us
If you have a privacy concern, complaint or a question for the Data Controller of The Dotty House, please contact us by using our Contact form for The Dotty House https://www.thedottyhouse.co.uk/contact/
Unless otherwise stated, The Dotty House is a data controller for personal data we collect through the services/products subject to this statement. Our address is The Dotty House, 1-3 Dryden Road, Gateshead, NE9 5HP, Telephone: 0191 487 3429.
Name*Email*
CAPTCHAConsent* By checking this box you agree to our privacy policy*PhoneThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
Follow us
Navigation
ChristmasOccasionsHisHersKidsHouse & HomeCards & Gift Bags
Quick Links
Visit Us
Shipping / Delivery
My Account / Login / Register
Contact Us
Home
ChristmasChristmas CardsChristmas WrappingOccasionsAnniversary GiftsBaby Shower GiftsChristening GiftsEngagement GiftsFather's DayGet Well Soon GiftsHousewarming GiftsNew Baby GiftsRetirement GiftsThank You GiftsThinking Of You GiftsWedding GiftsHisPersonalisedHersBagsGiftsHeadbandsJewelleryJoma BraceletsKey RingsKimono / WrapsPersonalisedScarvesKidsPersonalisedGifts for BabiesGifts for BoysGifts for GirlsJellycatHouse & HomeCushionsOutdoorPersonalised GiftsAlcohol RelatedHome AccessoriesHome FragrancePictures and PrintsCards & Gift BagsAdult Age Birthday CardsAnniversary CardsBaby Shower CardsBelated BirthdayBirthday CardsBlank Greetings CardsChildren's Age Birthday CardsChristening / Naming Day CardsCondolence CardsCongratulations/ Well Done CardsEngagement CardsFather's Day CardsFemale Relative Birthday CardsGeordie CardsGet Well Soon CardsGift Bags & WrapGood Luck CardsHere for You CardsLeaving / Bon Voyage CardsLockdown CardsMale Relative Birthday CardsNew Baby CardsNew Home CardsNew Job CardsRetirement CardsThank You CardsThinking of You CardWedding CardsX-Rated Top Shelf Cards
Visit Us
Shipping / Delivery
My Account / Login / Register
Contact
This site uses cookies
We use cookies to give you the best browsing experience.
We require your consent to store cookies for certain categories of functionality.
